The girl behind the name.
Amy is a documentary, music film directed by Asif Kapadia.
A documentary on the life of Amy Winehouse, the
immensely talented yet doomed songstress.
We see her from her teen years, where she already showed her singing abilities, to her
finding success and then her downward spiral into alcoholism and drugs.
Self (archive footage), played by Amy Winehouse.
Self, played by Mark Ronson.
Self, played by Tony Bennett.
Self, played by Pete Doherty.
Self, played by Juliette Ashby.
Self, played by Yasiin Bey.
Amy is a 2015 British documentary film directed by Asif
Kapadia and produced by James Gay-Rees.
The film covers English singer-songwriter Amy Winehouse's life and her struggle with substance abuse,
both before and after her career blossomed, and which eventually caused her death.
In February 2015, a teaser trailer based on the life of
Winehouse debuted at a pre-Grammys event.
David Joseph, CEO of Universal Music UK, announced that the
documentary titled Amy would be released later that year.
He further stated: "About two years ago we decided to make
a movie about her—her career and her life.
It's a very complicated and tender movie.
It tackles lots of things about family and media, fame, addiction, but most importantly, it captures the very heart of what she was about, which is
an amazing person and a true musical genius."
Amy premiered in the Midnight Screenings section of the 2015 Cannes Film Festival.
Distributed by the Altitude and A24, it was
released theatrically on 3 July 2015.
The film received critical acclaim, garnering 33 nominations and winning a total of 30 awards, including Best Documentary at the 28th European Film Awards, Best
Documentary at the 69th British Academy Film Awards, Best Music Film at the 58th Grammy Awards and the Best Documentary Feature at the 88th Academy Awards.
The success of Amy and the music of its soundtrack also led Winehouse to her second
posthumous nomination at the 2016 BRIT Awards for British Female Solo Artist.
The film explores themes of jazz, drug addiction,
rehabilitation, overdose, jazz singer or musician.